# JAMES R. PRIEST

La Canada, CA 91011 • 626-240-9970

james-priest@outlook.com • linkedin.com/in/jamespriestdeveloper • github.com/james-priest

### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Frontend TypeScript, React, REST API and Database Developer with 25 years' experience building web applications

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

UI: Responsive UI/UX Design, WAI-ARIA Accessibility

API: REST API Design with Python, Node.js

Database: SQL Server/MySQL, NoSQL MongoDB

Cloud: AWS, Azure, Google, GitHub, GitLab, RestDB

Frontend: React, Redux, Styled Components, Tailwind CSS

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C#, SQL, RegEx

**Data:** Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Views

Build: Vite, Webpack, Vercel, ESBuild, Rollup

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Everbridge, Inc.

Senior Software Engineer II

Pasadena, CA

10/2019 - 07/2024

Responsible for developing both internal and client-facing SaaS applications, dashboards, and visualizations for business-critical decision making. Reported to Director of Data Analytics in the role of Chief Frontend Engineer for the Analytics, Usage Reporting, and Business Process Intelligence teams.

- Internal Usage Dashboards Increased profitability by creating internal BI analytics web application to measure company costs and set product pricing.
  - Built using React, TypeScript, Ant Design, Vite, Looker, Python for REST API.
- **Resilience Insights** Collaborated on development of SaaS application to provide real-time Risk Analysis resulting in new revenue stream.
  - Built using React, TypeScript, Styled Components, Google Maps, Zustand, Webpack, Looker.
- Location Risk Assessment Developed interactive mapping solution to visualize location-based risk events and assist in critical decision-making allowing customers to maximize business operations security. Built using React, TypeScript, Redux, Google Maps, Bing Maps, Java, ElasticSearch.
- **EB Suite Usage Reporting** Created visualization and reporting system to provide customer usage and consumption forecasting resulting in faster contract renewal rates.
  - Built using React, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Recharts, Styled Components, Webpack, module federation for micro-frontend design.

Velodea Pasadena, CA

Senior Web Application Developer

04/2006 - 03/2017

Served as Solutions Architect, Programming Lead, and Database Developer for digital marketing agency. Designed and build over 70 website solutions across a variety of platforms, technologies, and languages for Fortune 500 companies such as Shell, Qualcomm, Sprint, Maserati, Fox, Miramax, ABC, J. Walter Thompson, and Edelman. Reported directly to CEO and Managing Director.

- **Beechcraft Corporation** (beechcraft.txtav.com) As a direct extension of Beechcraft IT, duties included web application development, database design, and content management. Responsible for building and maintaining Beechcraft corporate website as well as many applications to support Sales and Marketing. Built using **ASP.NET**, **C#**, database design, **SQL Server**, **Bootstrap**, **JavaScript**, **jQuery**.
- Shell Eco-marathon Live (<a href="shellecomarathon.com">shellecomarathon.com</a>) Created social and streaming media platform to serve live coverage of Shell's multi-national Eco-marathon events. Site featured event video, twitter feeds, online polls, and contest standings. Events were live streamed through our CDN to 50+ countries worldwide.

JAMES R. PRIEST PAGE 2

Built using PHP/My SQL, Live Video Streaming, REST APIs (Facebook, Twitter, YouTube), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery.

- Flex Ed (<u>flexed.com</u>) Implemented large-scale Learning Management System to track and schedule education of 85,000 students resulting in two-fold increase of student registrations for education institution servicing California, Nevada, and Texas.
   Built using Linux/Apache, PHP/MySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery, stored procedures, triggers, MySQL functions.
- **ABC Studios Live Stream** Designed and built streaming media platform providing executives and stakeholders the ability to monitor camera feeds at each remote soundstage in real-time through secured web application access.

Built using ASP.NET, C#, Flash, ActionScript, FMS/WMS streaming with F4V/WMV media encoding.

# devAware Technology Solutions

La Cañada, CA

Founder, Lead Developer

07/2002 - 03/2006

devAware specialized in .NET and Windows DNA application development for the web and desktop. As founder and lead developer, my role was that of information architect, systems designer, and application developer.

- Sony VIAO Desktop Contracted by Sony to build advanced kiosk application for nationwide rollout to all Best Buy, Circuit City, Good Guys, and Fry's Electronics stores. The application locked down OS access through registry and group policy modifications while allowing customer interaction with the desktop and suite of Sony applications. Usage statistics were logged, uploaded, and accessed through secure login. Built using: ASP.NET, ADO.NET, C#, Win32, VB COM, SQL Server, IIS, Windows registry customization.
- Xtreme Desktops Applications Develop application framework for a series of Flash-based desktop
  experiences. Components consisted of .NET HTTP server applications to gather usage statistics for upload
  to centralized analytics server. Responsible for custom built analytics system and test lab
  with IIS, ASP.NET, and SQL Server.

Built using C#, ADO.NET, VB COM objects, InstallShield scripting, IIS, SQL Server, test lab methodologies.

# The Velodea Group / Bleu22 Studios

Milan, Italy and Los Angeles, CA

Lead Software Developer

07/2000 - 07/2002

Served as lead developer and director of The Velodea Group's Velotek division with job responsibilities spanning web application development, systems architecture, and network infrastructure. Reported to CEO and VP of Product Development.

- VeloTrack Designed SaaS application suite offering behavioral tracking, email list management,
  registration, surveying, and demographic-based site usage reporting. VeloTrack boasted the ability to
  capture millions of page views per day in a manner transparent to the end user. The system was designed
  to be highly customizable and intuitive to allow non-technical clients the ability to generate reports as
  well as create surveys and construct email marketing campaigns. All data was made available through
  HTTP as a REST API for integration into client applications.
  - Built as **modularized system** developed over two years consisting of equal parts **Google Analytics**, **Constant Contact**, **Mail Chimp**, **WordPress** and **Salesforce** before those systems existed.
- VeloTeam Built asset management system that facilitating communication and collaboration between
  project teams and clients. The system managed user accounts, tracked incident resolutions, and provided
  automated email notifications. Over 100 customized instances were rolled out for clients such as Sony,
  Miramax, Qualcomm, and Toshiba.
  - The VeloTeam Suite provided capabilities of **Basecamp, DropBox, JIRA**, and **GitHub**. It offered **project management, document sharing, version control, bug tracking/issue resolution** and **client communications**.

JAMES R. PRIEST PAGE 3

Microsoft, Inc.

Release Program Manager

Redmond, WA

11/1998 - 06/2000

As a key member of Microsoft's Product Release team, responsibilities included application development, system design and project management for release of Microsoft product to the marketplace. Reported to Director of Product Release.

- Release to Web Built web application system that served as primary release mechanism for all products available to Microsoft's Download Center. System boasted an average of 1000 releases per month and tracked workflow, sign-off, QA, and virus scan. All releases were vaulted to centralized repo within the Software Release Labs and resulted in fulfilling Microsoft's need to release product in under 3 hours.
- Media Shipment Tracking Created system to gather and track all media shipments made to Microsoft's
  third-party manufacturers. This allowed manufacturing facilities to plan production cycles as well as track
  the progress of any shipment. System consisted of multiple SQL Server databases in each of Microsoft's
  regions of operation. Data was input through web-based frontend and warehoused three times daily to
  coincide with the close of business at Microsoft's American, European and Asian operating centers.

Systems were developed using **multi-tier design architecture** and components were built for reusability following a **component object model**. Additional responsibilities ranged from **systems analysis**, **application prototyping**, **database design**, **user-interface design**, **functional specification**, and **technical documentation**.

### ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Phillips Research Laboratory**

Web Application Developer

**Albuquerque, NM** 10/1997 – 10/1998

Hired as Lead Intranet Developer for the U.S. Air Force's Phillips Research Lab at Kirtland Air Force Base. Job functions involved design and implementation of all web-based client/server applications as well as systems analysis, database programming and graphic design. Technologies used included ASP, SQL, Java and ActiveX development. Also responsible for NT, IIS, and SQL Server administration and configuration.

**Intel Corporation** 

Web Application Developer

Rio Rancho, NM

06/1997 - 10/1997

Contracted to design and develop a web-based reporting system responsible for generating statistical information for Intel University. Utilized **ASP, SQL, and custom developed ActiveX DLLs**. The system was implemented worldwide upon its completion.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

React Nanodegree (React, Redux, React Native), Udacity	6-month term	2019
Google Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree, Udacity	6-month term	2018
JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, FCC	300 hours	2017
Responsive Web Design, FCC	300 hours	2017

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science**, Computer Information Systems (BSc CIS)

DeVry University, Pomona, CA (1997)